

# **Justus Will**

## Machine Learning Researcher

Irvine, CA 92617, USA justuswill.com · jcwill@uci.edu

es GitHub, ORCID, LinkedIn,
Google Scholar

#### **Skills**

Fast Learner

Creative Problem Solving

Teamwork

### Languages

German

English

French

Spanish

Swedish

### **Programming**

Python, R, MATLAB, Java, C/C++, HTML/CSS/JS, SQL. Torch, TF, CUDA, Slurm, etc.

#### **Publications**

ClimSim: A Large Multi-Scale Dataset For Hybrid Physics-ML Climate Emulation, NeurIPS 2023 (Best Paper Award)

Understanding and Visualizing Droplet Distributions in Simulations of Shallow Clouds, NeurIPS Workshop 2023

#### Interests

Snowboarding, Surfing, Volleyball, Travel, Cooking

### **Profile**

PhD student at University of California, Irvine, advised by <u>Stephan Mandt</u>. Expert programming knowledge with 10+ years experience across diverse languages including a long history of successful machine learning projects. Research with focus on Deep Generative Models, Neural Data Compression, and the application of Machine Learning to Climate Science.

### **Education**

B. Sc. Mathematics / B. Sc. Computer Science, TU Kaiserslautern, Germany

2017 - 2020, GPA: 3.92 / 3.92

M. Sc. Mathematics, TU Kaiserslautern (Lund University, Sweden)

2020 - 2022, GPA: 3.92

Ph.D. Computer Science, UC Irvine, USA

2023 - Current

## **Experience**

### Student / Teaching Assistant, TU Kaiserslautern / UC Irvine

September 2018 - Current

Supported 1000+ students across 10+ courses in various roles as supervisor, mentor, advisor, educator, and examiner. Topics include probability theory, statistics, scientific computing, programming, machine learning, and more.

### Research Assistant, German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence

October 2019 - May 2020

Developed an evolutionary algorithm to optimize the topology and hyperparameters of convolutional networks. Designed a front and back end providing 50+ users intuitive access to the local GPU computation cluster.

### Research Assistant, TU Kaiserslautern, Machine Learning Group

October 2020 - December 2022

Conducted various research of use in chemical process engineering and beyond. Developed a new tensor completion framework to make predictions for sparse tabular data and style-transfer methods for time series. Ongoing collaboration, including as invited speaker at a Dagstuhl seminar.